字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
在我打败极速并拯救了多元宇宙后
After defeating Zoom and saving the multiverse,
我跑回到了过去
I ran back in time
创造出了另一条时间线  闪点
and created the alternate timeline, Flashpoint.
我恢复了时间线原来的状态
I restored the timeline to how it was,
但发现有些事却不一样了
only to find things weren't as I left them.
我给我们的世界带来了新的威胁
I brought new threats to our world,
而我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to stop them.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
我们得考虑回到我们的地球了
We have to think about getting back to our Earth.
我们已经来这够久了
We've been here long enough.
整个多元宇宙里有这么多哈里森·威尔斯
A whole multiverse of Harrison Wells out there.
需要一个吗  那就去找吧
You want one? Let's go get one.
幽默的威尔斯
Wells with a sense of humor.
-哈里森  -你可以叫我HR
- Harrison. - Call me H.R.
旧的不去  新的不来
Out with the old, in with the new.
你怎么在这里
What are you doing here?
"朱利安·艾伯特
"Julian Albert,
超能力者犯罪现场鉴证专家"
meta-human CSI specialist""
我不信任你  而我不喜欢我不信任的事物
I don't trust you, and I don't like things that I don't trust.
去年我是怎么和这人合作的
How have I worked with this guy for the past year?
你总是这么说
You say that all the time.
不如今晚一起吃顿晚餐吧
Do you maybe want to grab some dinner tonight?
我今晚要和孩子们一起看电影
I got movie night with my kids tonight.
改天再约如何
Rain check?
你是唯一在我干扰了时间线之后
You were the only one who wasn't affected
没有受到影响的人
when I messed with the timeline.
你不用每天早晨都这样的
You know you don't need to do this every morning, right?
我也只能做这个了
Oh, come on, it's the least I can do.
我爱乔  可是
I mean, I love Joe, but at some point,
他也需要自己的空间
man needs his own space,
在我找到新住处之前  就住你这了
and until I find my own space, that means your space.
这是我向你表示的感激之情
So as a token of my appreciation,
两个双面煎蛋  培根  吐司
two eggs over easy, bacon, toast--
我记不得了  你喜不喜欢抹黄油
I can't remember, do you like it buttered or not?
巴里  我自己来抹黄油就好
Barry, sometimes a man just wants to butter his own bread.
好吧  对不起  我只是
Okay, sorry. I was just--
嗯  你说得对  我
Yeah, no, you're right, I--
别误会  好吧
Look, don't get it twisted, okay?
我喜欢让你住在这  你这个客人表现得很好
I love having you here. You're a great guest.
但是我不太喜欢另一个客人
I'm not sure how I feel about our other visitor, though.
威尔斯
Wells?
"请叫我HR"
"Please, call me H.R."
这么说你不喜欢他
So you don't like him?
我也不是非常不喜欢他
Oh, it's not so much that I don't like him.
只是  他说话的方式  总感觉怪怪的
I just-- the way he says things, there's something about him.
我也说不出来是什么
I don't know what it is.
伙计  他才刚来几天  让他适应一下
Dude, he's only been here a few days; let him settle in.
我知道我们以前那位威尔斯是坏人
I know we've had our Wells issues in the past,
但是你也不能不再相信别人了
but you can't just stop trusting everybody
或者不给他们一个机会
or giving them chances.
你不能这样
You know? You can't live like that.
说得对  智者有智言
This is true. Wise words from a wise man.
乔说的
Joe Knowledge.
我带走吃吧
I'm gonna take this to go.
-好的  -一会见
- Okay. All right. - Uh, I'll see you there.
好  我可以送你去
Yeah. Oh, I can take you.
不用  不用
No. No.
我今天自己开车
I'm gonna drive myself today.
好的  好的
Yeah, cool. Cool.
有什么要帮忙的
Can I help you?
我来见唐豪瑟医生
I'm here to see Dr. Tannhauser.
你有预约吗
Do you have an appointment?
没有  不过我相信她会见我的
No, but I'm pretty sure she'll see me.
请跟她说凯特琳·斯诺来了
You can just tell her Caitlin Snow is here.
唐豪瑟医生很忙的
Dr. Tannhauser's a very busy woman.
我想你能理解的
I'm sure you can understand.
谢谢你的尽职  杰基
I appreciate the diligence, Jackie,
不过凯特琳可以随时来见我
but Caitlin's always welcome here,
尽管我希望她能提前打个电话
even if I wish she'd call first.
我也很高兴见到你  妈妈
Nice to see you too, Mom.
什么风把你吹来了
So what brings you here?
我没忘记你的生日吧
I didn't forget your birthday, did I?
我很确定我寄过生日卡片了
I'm pretty sure I sent a card.
是的  四月份寄的
You did... in April.
谢谢
Thank you.
我读了你那篇关于低温医疗应用的新论文
Look, I read your new paper on applications in cryo-medicine,
我觉得你能帮上忙
and I think you might be able to help.
我都不知道你在尖端科研实验室
I had no idea you kept up on the literature
还看论文
over at S.T.A.R. Labs.
是叫这个名字  对吧
That's still what it's called, right?
是的  我有个病人需要你的帮助
Yes, and I have a patient who could use your help.
如果你把病人的资料发过来的话
Well, if you want to send over the file,
我有空的时候会看一下的
I'll be happy to take a look when I have a chance,
但现在  我有个股东大会
but right now, I have a shareholder meeting
-要准备  所以  -妈妈
- to prepare for and-- - Mom!
我就是那个病人
I'm the patient.
取消我所有的预约
Cancel my appointments,
让奈杰尔去生物实验室等我
and have Nigel meet me in the bio-lab.
我们有工作要做
We have work to do.
闪电侠
第三季
第五集
华丽的一天
Sumptuous day.
在这个地球上  应该说
No, on this Earth, I believe you say...
-早上好  -早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
确实很好  是吧
And it is, isn't it? I mean...
你们地球上的音乐  触动心弦
The music on your Earth, well, it strikes a chord,
并不是双关
no pun intended.
请随便吃
Please, help yourself.
一个团队只有吃得好
I find a crew works best
休息好才能工作得好
when it's well-fed and well-rested.
那些咖啡也是给我们准备的吗
Are those coffees for us too?
是的  韦斯特小姐
Yes indeed, Miss West.
我昨天晚上看了你们的账单
I took the liberty of reading through your ledgers last night.
信息量很多  不过看看我学到了什么吧
A lot of information to absorb, but let's see how I did.
脱脂奶茶拿铁咖啡
Skim milk chai latte.
-不错  -不错
- Okay. - Okay.
美式冰咖啡加了两份  不对
And an iced Americano with two--no,
-三份意式特浓  -好样的
- three shots of espresso. - Boom.
就是这样  沃尔特
That happened, Walter.
-沃利  -沃利
- Wally. - Wally.
至于我健步如飞的朋友
Now, for my fleet-of-foot friend--
你最好继续喝低咖啡因咖啡
you'd best stick to decaf.
这样也许最好
Probably for the best, yeah.
三藩西斯科
San Francisco.
我准备了一杯法国焙火咖啡
I have "Prepar-e" a French roast
加了少许奶精
with a touch of creamer.
-非常感谢  -不客气
- Thank you so much. - You're welcome.
你们知道吗  在我的地球上
Did you know, on my Earth,
咖啡作物因为枯萎病而灭绝了
coffee crop was wiped out by blight?
所以又多了一个待在这个地球的理由
I mean, that's one more reason to stay on this Earth,
仅仅是为了咖啡
for the coffee alone.
前提是你留下来的话
Yeah, though that's if you stay.
如果我留下来  时间是极为重要的
If I stay. Time is of the essence.
我建议开始一连串的团队信任建立活动
Here's what I propose, a series of team-building exercises.
我已经在整个实验室里周围
Now, I've hidden a series of clues
藏好了一连串的线索
all around the facility.
我的建议是
What I propose is,
我们分成两组
we break into two groups, all right,
你们可以选一个伙伴
and you can pick a partner; you're--
好  好
Okay, okay.
不得不打断你  HR  我不喜欢这个
I have to stop you, H.R. I am not feeling this.
是焙火的问题吧  我就该用黑咖啡
It's the roast, isn't it? I should have gone with a dark--
和焙火关系  焙火的很好喝
No, it's not the roast. The roast is fine.
我们之间的信任
Our trust isn't something
不是靠游戏就能建立起来的
that you can just build with games.
-知道吗  -不
- Okay? - No.
这是三年来的积累
This is something that goes back three years.
是经过历炼之火
It's something that's been forged in fire,
有时还真身在火中
sometimes literally,
所以也许你最好别插手
so maybe you should just step back
就在一旁观察我们在这所做的事
and observe, see what we do here,
以及运作方式  懂吗
how we operate. Did you get that?
精辟的要点  我会好好想想
Excellent note. I'm gonna run with that.
话说凯特琳哪去了  你有没有...
Where's Caitlin, by the way? Have you--
-她之前在这里  -之前
- Yes. So she was here. - She was?
好了  我们聊过  她...
All right, yeah, you know, we talked, and she...
什么
What?
一口气喝了杯三份浓度的拿铁
Knocked back a triple-shot latte,
还给你们留了言  那我要
and she left you a message, so I'm gonna--
不如我放给你们听吧
I... yeah, let me just play it for you.
这机器和我地球上的不同
This is not the same as my Earth's.
完全不一样
This is a different--
好了
There it is.
是我
Hey, it's me.
我有些事要去处理
I've got some things I need to take care of.
几天后  我就会回来
I shouldn't be gone more than a few days.
看看没有我  你们是否能搞得定
See if you can get along without me.
别让西斯科碰我的冷冻披萨
Make sure Cisco doesn't touch my pizza pockets.
上面又没贴名字
Wasn't labeled.
好了  各位
Okay, you know what, guys?
我得去上班  我快迟到了
I got to go to work. I'm running late.
是的  我也应该去上班
Ooh, yeah. I got to do that too.
-走吧  -我也要开溜了
- Yeah, let's go. - I got to bail.
改天我们再做团队信任建立活动
You know, we'll do the team-building exercises another--
我会把线索藏在实验室里的
I'll leave the clues hidden in the facility.
好  你们那边怎么说回头见
Cool. How do you guys say "See you later" over there?
下次再聚
"Until next communion."
-好吧  回头见  -回头见
- All right, see you later. - See you later.
好奇怪
So weird.
辛格队长
进来
Come.
抱歉我迟到了
Hey, sorry I'm late.
我得去见一个人
I had to meet somebody and--
你可以把迟到加进清单里  队长
You can add tardiness to the list, Captain.
艾伦  我一直注意到你
Allen, it's been brought to my attention
未经许可  访问你同事的
that you've been giving yourself unauthorized access
案件文档
to your colleagues' case files.
你说什么
Excuse me?
还有多次违规
Along with multiple infractions,
屡次缺席
repeated absences,
整天不见人影
disappearing throughout the day,
电话中断  让人随意进入实验室
phone call interruptions, guests in the lab.
这张清单的名目还真不少啊  队长
The list is pretty extensive, Captain.
对不起  恕我直言
I'm sorry, with all due respect,
我按时完成工作的
I do my job here.
你的工作很出色  艾伦
You do good work here, Allen.
因此别以为这样就不必遵守规章制度
Don't put that in jeopardy by thinking
别让你的努力付诸东流
the rules don't apply to you.
明白吗
Understood?
明白  长官
Yes, sir.
抱歉  队长  就这样吗
Sorry, Captain, that's it?
长官  我列出八项不同的
Sir, I document eight different--
九项
Nine.
九项不同的违章行为
Nine different violations of regulations,
这么快就训完了吗
and he gets a 15-second talking-to?
你一定感觉良好吧
Must be nice.
说完了  你们走吧
We are done here. You can go.
告辞  队长
Captain.
你真这么喜欢打小报告吗
Were you really just being a tattletale?
-太不专业了吧  -你说得对
- That's bush league, man. - You know what? You're right.
愚昧如我  竟然认为规章能够约束
Silly me to think the rules actually apply
中城警局取证室的金童
to the golden boy of CCPD's crime lab.
警探  你好
Detective.
-他简直是无理取闹  -是啊
- He's unbelievable. - You know what?
但愿你们俩能少点互不相容
I wish you two could be a little less oil and water
多点彼此相容
and a little bit more oil and vinegar.
你们俩已经互掐了一年
You guys have been at each other's throats for a year now.
我受够了
That's just it.
从我的角度来看  才两个星期
From my perspective, it's been two weeks.
你是说在两个星期前
So you're saying that before two weeks ago,
你不是朱利安的敌人吗
you weren't Julian's enemy?
我是说两个星期前
I'm saying before two weeks ago,
朱利安根本都不存在
Julian didn't even exist.
是因为你的闪点
It's because of your Flashpoint.
我知道是因为闪点
I know it's because of the Flashpoint.
西斯科打来的
Cisco.
有什么重要事情吗
Hey, is this important?
我不知道  在闹市区有三十起
I don't know; does 30 hits downtown
超能力应用警告算吗
on the meta-human app count?
-我们面对的是什么  -什么都没有
- What are we looking at? - Well, nothing really.
十街区半径内的所有交通摄像头
Every traffic cam in a ten-block radius
都挂了  所以我们现在瞎了
suddenly went down, so we're flying blind,
而警报遍地图都是
and the hits are all over the map.
好吧  只有一个办法能看到
All right, well, there's one way to see
发生了什么  我得走了
what's going on. I got to go.
大部分骚动来自于港区
Most of the chatter's coming from the harbor district.
好了  我到了  这里可真糟糕
All right, I'm here. It's a bad scene, man.
你应该就在正中央  巴里
You should be right on top of it, Barry.
是什么
What is it?
是个  怪物
It's a...monster?
伙计们  听得到了吗
Guys, did you hear me?
中城有一只怪物
There is a monster in Central City.
究竟有多大
What are we talking?
姚明大小还是巨人安德雷
Yao Ming size or Andre the Giant?
不  那是  一只真正的怪物
No, it's, like, an actual monster.
-那家伙怎么出来的  -我完全不知道
- What even makes that? - I don't even know that.
尖端实验室卫星  给我看看
S.T.A.R. Labs satellite, show me something.
你在地球十九见过这种东西吗
You ever see anything like that on Earth-19?
你想让我旁观  我就只旁观
You want me to observe. I'll just observe.
爱瑞丝  你来这里干什么
Iris, what are you doing here?
做报道
Working on a story,
而且据我所知  你不需要
and last time I checked, you don't need
超级速度和红衣服来帮助人
super-speed and a red suit to help people.
好吧  快离开这里
All right, get out of here.
我要试着阻止那玩意
I'm gonna try to stop that thing.
快啊  快啊  快啊
Come on, come on, come on.
西斯科  它去哪了
Cisco, where'd it go?
我看不到就没法追踪
Can't track it if I can't see it.
知道你可以怎么办吗  你可以用耳朵
Know what you could do? Could use your ears.
我的耳朵
My ears?
那是什么声音
What's that sound?
是车警报  我可以用车警报
It's a car alarm; I can use the car alarms
来追踪怪物行进的方向
to track the direction the monster's heading in.
找到它了  向北三个街区
We got him. Head north three blocks.
我看不到它了
I lost him.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
-我不明白  -我不明白
- I don't get it. - I don't get it.
我们遇到的每一个超能力者
Every meta-human we've encountered
就都只是有超能力的人
has been exactly that, meta-human,
所以这东西是哪来的
so where did this thing come from?
我不知道它是哪来  老兄
I don't know where it came from, man.
我就  它就那么消失了
I just--it just vanished.
我就知道这些  它就那么没了
That's all I know. It was gone.
但根据我的经验  事情总是不同的
Yeah, but in my experience, things are always different.
-什么  -然后他们就出现了
- What? - Than they appear.
肯定有什么能让那鬼东西
There must be a reason the darn thing
就这么凭空消失
can just disappear like that.
也许那鬼东西有某种隐身机制
Maybe the darn thing's got some kind of cloaking mechanism.
这想法不错  但现在
That's a good idea, but right now,
我更想讨论"我们怎么阻止它"
I would settle for "How can we stop it?"
对  当然了
Yes, obviously.
-那该怎么办  -我不知道
- Just how? - I don't know.
我们又没有神奇的怪物套索
We don't have a magic monster lasso.
但你知道  我们可以...
But you know what we could--
抱歉我忘了  我只是  我只能说旁观
Sorry. I forgot. I'm just--I'm just observing.
别  HR  请说
No, H.R., please.
我们现在公开接受点子
We're open to any idea right now.
在我的地球上  我们有碳纤维做的绳子
On my Earth, we have ropes made out of carbon fiber.
它们非常轻  但强度足够拖动战舰
They are ultralight but strong enough to pull a battleship;
我们可以用那个来制住它
we could restrain it with that.
怎样  你们怎么想
Right? What do you think?
-好啊  我想...  -好
- Okay, I think it's... - Okay.
我想值得试一下
I think it's worth a shot;
我们可以在我工作室做一个
we can spin it down in my workshop.
好的  棒
Yes. Good.
对了  还有其他一些奇怪的事
Yeah, there was something else that was weird, though.
这东西经过的时候我看到一个变压器爆炸了
I-I saw a transformer explode as this thing passed by it.
-真是奇怪  -那有什么可奇怪的
- That is weird. - What's weird about that?
怪物碰都没碰到它
Monster didn't even lay a finger on it.
在怪物到那之前就爆了
It exploded before it got to it.
有点让我想起了希区柯克的某个电影
Kind of reminds me of that Hitchcock movie
里边的临时演员在枪响之前捂上了耳朵
where the extra covers his ears before the gun goes off.
你们这个地球上也有希区柯克
You have Hitchcock on this Earth?
太棒了
Oh, brilliant.
"泰坦尼克号谋杀案"
"Murder on the Titanic"!
"谁干的  谁在乎  我们要淹死了"
"Who did it? Who cares? We're drowning""
那畜生肯定是释放了某种电磁脉冲
The beast must emit some kind of electrical pulse.
有没有办法能让我看看那变压器
Is there a way I could get a look at that transformer?
不行  那整个地方都是犯罪现场了
No. It's--the whole place is a crime scene now
朱利安负责掌管
with Julian in charge of it.
朱利安  是谁来着
Julian. Who's that?
那个你不喜欢的鉴证科家伙  对吧
That's the CSI guy you don't like, right?
我是说
I mean...
好吧  行
Yeah, all right.
他太棒了
He's great.
抱歉  手比较凉
Sorry, cold hands.
我都没感觉到
I didn't even notice.
对了  我叫奈杰尔
I'm Nigel, by the way.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
我们会帮助你解决这事的  凯特琳
We're gonna help you figure this out, Caitlin.
咱们去实验室吧
Let's get you to the lab.
这是什么
What's this?
是测试你的能力如何影响分子运动的
It's to test how your ability affects molecular motion.
那柱体是固态钨
That shaft is solid tungsten,
被加热到超过两千摄氏度
and it's heated to over 2,000 degrees centigrade.
我想让你冷却它
I want you to cool it down,
当我们了解你如何办到的时候
and when we determine how you can do that,
我们就可以想办法帮助你了
we can figure out the best way to help you.
短时间内我们就只能做这么多
Best we could do in such little time.
所以你在这里待了一个小时
So this is where you've been for the last hour.
我可为了这个重新安排了行程  凯瑟琳
I had to reschedule my day for this, Caitlin.
这里很多事都需要我的关注
A lot of things around here require my attention.
我记得
I remember.
你准备好了就上
Whenever you're ready.
别有所保留
Don't hold back.
朱利安
Hey, Julian.
你看到这个了吗
You seen this?
怪物侵袭中城
有超能力毁坏城市已经够糟的了
It's bad enough we have the metas destroying the city.
现在又要担心这个
Now we have this thing to worry about.
我问你刚才那一个小时去哪里了你会回答吗
Is there any point in me asking where you've been for the last hour?
或是我应该假定
Or should I just assume the rules
你还是不按规矩来
still don't apply to you?
我刚才
I was--I--
好吧
Yes, okay.
哥们  我知道
Look, hey, man, so I know that...
我们刚认识的时候就给对方印象不好
you and I, we got off on the wrong foot.
我们后来也不怎么和睦
We never managed to find the right one,
这我接受
and I'll take that.
八成是我的错  但我
That's probably my fault, but I just--
我不想再这样继续下去了
I don't want things to be like that anymore, you know?
我希望我们的关系能有改观
I-I'd...like it if things changed.
有趣  我记得你说过这话
It's funny, 'cause I remember you saying
就在你把那个案子
something similar to that right before you stole
从我这里抢走之前
the case from underneath me.
你知道和一个不守规矩的人一起共事
Do you have idea what it's like to work side by side with someone
是什么感觉吗
with such little regard for the rules?
你甚至可能会破坏我的工作
You may very well be contaminating my work.
这就是为什么我想向你学习
That's exactly why I want to learn from you.
我没懂你什么意思
I don't follow.
我只是  每次读了你的报告书
I just--you know, whenever I read your reports,
都能感到你的证据收集手段
it's clear that your evidence collection techniques
比我高明多了
are far superior to mine.
继续
Go on.
我也说不好  如果我能当你一天的跟班
I don't know; I mean, if I could just shadow you for a day,
问问你问题
maybe ask a few questions,
我觉得这样真的能让我的技术
I think that you could really help bring my skills
更上一层楼
up to...snuff.
你觉得怎样
What do you say?
抱歉
Sorry.
如果我不要这个实验室了呢
What if I gave up the lab?
楼下有个储藏间我可以改造一下
There's a storeroom downstairs that I could convert,
如果你让我跟进这个案子  实验室归你
so if you let me follow you on this case, lab's yours.
实验室归我
Lab's mine?
好  成交
Okay. Deal.
不过你不能拖我后腿
You can't slow me down, though.
-我绝不会  -那行  我会给你打电话的
- I would never. - All right. I'll call you.
你获得能力多长时间了
How long have you had these abilities?
大概是几个月之前开始显露了吧
They started manifesting a few months ago,
但是我想应该是
but I'm assuming I got them
粒子加速器爆炸的时候获得的
when the particle accelerator exploded,
和其他超能力者一样
just like all the other metas.
你谁也没有告诉吗
And you haven't told anyone?
只跟你说了
Just you.
我说过的  你就不应该去尖端实验室工作
I told you, you never should have taken that job at S.T.A.R. Labs.
你本可以留在这里
You could have stayed here,
能接触到世界顶级设备
had access to world-class facilities.
那我的工作
And have all of my work be
就都逃不出你的名声了
in the shadow of your reputation.
当然了  只有你遇到麻烦的时候
Of course, the only time you need your mother
才会需要你的母亲
is when you're in trouble.
你那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
得了吧  亲爱的
Oh, come on, darling.
你跑到中城去
You ran off to Central City
跟那个臭名昭著的假货扮演科学家玩
to play scientist with that disgraced quack.
我想为我自己立身扬名
I was trying to make a name for myself.
三年了  名在哪里
For three years, barely a word,
现在遇上麻烦了  来找我了
until trouble hits, and then here you come,
走进那扇门  希望自己的妈咪
walking through the door and expecting Mommy
放下生活中的一切去帮你
to drop everything in her life to try to fix it.
你根本不知道我经历了什么
You have no idea what I've been through..
唐豪瑟博士  你来看看这个
Dr. Tannhauser, look at this.
她吸收了所有的能量
She's absorbed all that energy?
怎么会
How?
我还不确定  但如果我们能弄明白这个
I'm not sure yet, but if we can figure that out,
那将会颠覆我们现在所做的一切
this could change everything we're doing here.
然后闪电侠  是我的闪电侠  不是你的
So then the Flash--my Flash, again, not your Flash--
我们想了个计划召集所有剩下的超能力者
we hatched a plan to gather all the remaining meta-humans
到一个地方一决高下
into one place for a final showdown.
我们称之为"超能力者大战"  异常壮阔
They called it "World War M”. It was glorious.
体育场两侧分立两种势力
Two forces on opposing sides of the stadium.
现场气氛紧张
The tension built. No.
就像那个电影
It was like that movie
那个角斗士带领其他角斗士的
where the gladiator was the lead gladiator.
那个电影叫什么
What was that called?
《角斗士》
"Gladiator."
这名字更好  在我的地球
That's better; on my Earth,
那电影叫《大汗淋漓》  那名字不行
it was called "Sweaty Men," And that didn't take.
两股势力在互冲开战  当时他们...
So the two forces charge into battle, and when they do--
-我要歇会儿  -好啊  我们出去走走
- I need to take a five. - Yeah, let's get out of here.
-我们休息一下  -我要一个人去
- Let's take a break. - By myself.
好啊  你去吧  我继续弄这个东西
Yeah, you go ahead. I'll keep working on this.
日志AAA:2
So entry AAA:2.
计划进行中  人物已经就位
Plan is proceeding. Characters are in place.
还没有人看出我为什么来到这里
Nobody seems the wiser as to why I'm here.
我要对这次袭击做个目击证人报道
I had to give a witness report on the attack,
我就想我们来个午饭约会吧
and I thought I would make it a lunch date.
好  我腾个地方
Yeah, cool. Clear a spot.
-我们开吃吧  -好的
- Let's do this. - Ahh. Yeah.
和朱利安关系好点了吗
Are things any better with Julian?
我的天啊  就好像每一次
Oh, my God, it's like, every time
我试图去了解这个人的时候  他就做些
I try to get to know the guy, he does something
让我很难办的事情
that makes it really hard to.
我现在知道的就只有他不喜欢超能力者
All I know now is that he dislikes meta-humans
和不喜欢我的程度一样
about as much as he dislikes me.
或许你应该换位思考
Maybe you should try and see things from his perspective.
或许他不喜欢你和超能力者是有原因的
He might have a reason to dislike both of you
只是你不清楚是什么原因
that you don't know anything about.
你刚才这是像乔一样唠叨我了吗
Did you just hit me with a Joe-ism?
有时候他说的时候对的  有时候不对
Well, sometimes he's right. Sometimes he's not.
-是啊  -说起这个
- Yeah. - Speaking of which,
我刚才在楼下看到他了
I just saw him downstairs,
他正在和地方检察官说话
and he was talking to the DA.
他拒绝了跟她的约会
He blew off a date with her.
我看到他上周就这样了
I saw him do the same thing last week.
我也不清楚  可能他没那么喜欢她吧
I don't know. Maybe he's not into her.
不是  他喜欢她
No, he's into her.
我问他是否对她有意思
I mean, when I asked him about her,
他只是叫我走开
he basically told me to buzz off.
你不会那么轻易走开的  对吧
You're not too good at buzzing off, are you?
不  涉及到我爸爸的时候  当然不会
Nope. When it comes to my dad, no.
朱利安·艾伯特
艾伦
来富尔顿街和第二街
交叉口找我
越快越好
艾伯特
看看是谁来消息了
Well, look who it is.
看样子我有一个从朱利安的角度
Looks like I have an opportunity to see things
看问题的机会
from Julian's perspective....
就是现在
Right now.
午餐不能陪你了  我得走了
Sorry about lunch. I got to go.
一会儿见  我要这个
See you later. Oh, I need that.
如果你一直动来动去  我找不到血管的
If you don't stop squirming, I'll never find a vein.
现在你又要化验什么
What exactly are you testing for now?
任何能帮我们理解
Any polymorphism that could help us understand
你是如何可以从分子中吸收那么多能量
how you're able to absorb that much energy
来制造极冷环境的基因多态性
from molecules to create gelid surroundings.
你知道我已经做过这些化验了吧
You realize I've run all of these tests already?
那你干什么还来这里呢
Then what was the point of coming here?
说真的  妈妈
Seriously, Mom?
我怕极了我会变成什么样子
I'm terrified of what I'm becoming.
你知道你一次都没问过我是什么感受吗
You realize you haven't asked me once how I'm feeling?
我在试着不受感情的左右
I'm trying to keep emotion out of this.
相信我  这对你我都有好处
Believe me, it's for your benefit as much as it is mine.
对  因为这就是你的专长  对吧
Right, because that's your specialty, isn't it?
冷漠  就像以前...
Being cold, just like after--
以前什么
After what?
爸爸去世之后
After Dad died.
为了救你爸爸我尽了全力
I did everything I could to save your father.
同时你也失去了女儿
Well, you lost your daughter at the same time.
是你主动离开的  凯特琳
You're the one who went away, Caitlin.
因为我不得不走
Because I had to.
你知道在爸爸病了之后
You realize you never acted like my mother again
你就没有母亲的样子了吗
after Dad got sick?
你几乎都不正眼看我
You would barely even look at me.
我没能承受那些痛苦
I...couldn't handle the pain.
工作让我度过了那段日子
My work got me through it.
那样失去一个人
Losing someone like that,
你完全无法理解我的感受
you have no idea what that feels like.
实际上  我理解
Actually, I do.
我的丈夫一年多前去世了
My husband died over a year ago.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
你有什么发现
What do you got?
我说快点儿来  但这也...
I said get here quick, but that was...
比我想的快
quicker than I expected.
对啊  是那个...
Oh, no, yeah, it was a...
优步司机开得很疯狂
crazy Uber driver.
根据爆炸方式
Well, the blast pattern
和绝缘体上的痕迹表明
and the scoring on the insulation suggests
这是电涌导致的爆炸
that it was a power surge that blew it out.
所以说是个意外
So it's a coincidence?
我不这么认为  不过我会弄个清楚的
I highly doubt it. But I'll figure it out.
这个城市该有人收拾一下这些超能力者了
Someone in this city has to do something about these metas.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
我们有全部的警力
We have a whole police force
出动来阻止这些超能力者
working to stop these metas.
不对  你有闪电侠
No, you have The Flash.
你讨厌的不止是做坏事的超能力者
So it's not just bad metas you don't like.
所有超能力者都讨厌
It's all the metas.
我只是说因为有他
I'm just saying that because of him,
整个警察部门变得懒洋洋的
the police department has got lethargic.
我是说  那么努力干什么
I mean, why do anything at all
反正每次闪电侠都能够转危为安
if The Flash is gonna save the day every time?
就跟你不守规矩一样
It's a bit like you with rule breaking--
稳定一阵子  然后现在又懒散马虎
a momentary fix, and now you're lazy, sloppy.
好吧  谢谢
Cool. Thanks.
我认为闪电侠实际上
I think The Flash is actually
鼓舞了这座城市
a source of inspiration for the city.
我认为他给了人希望
I think he kind of provides hope.
这是我们意见不一的
Yes, well, that's one of many things
众多事情中的一件  艾伦
that we'll have to disagree on, Allen.
怎么  你看到了什么吗
What? You see something?
一种规律
A pattern.
这个生物的运动  一开始看起来是随机的
The creature's movements, they seemed random at first,
但是他们在特定的区域内
but they were contained to a prescribed area.
就像这生物被困在了看不见的栅栏里
You know, like the creature was stuck in an invisible fence.
交通摄像头坏了 对吧
Traffic cameras were down, right?
也许是它被什么人观察或者操控着
Maybe it was being watched or controlled by somebody
需要让它保持在视野可见范围内
that needed to keep it in visual range the entire time?
限制生物的活动在可见范围内
Constricting the creature's movements to the line of sight.
这倒讲通了
That actually makes sense.
也许你还是有脑子的  艾伦
Maybe there is a brain in there after all, Allen.
调度中心  我是犯罪现场鉴证员
Dispatch, this is CSI.
请求紧急支援
I'm requesting immediate backup.
怪物出现在港口附近
The monster has been sighted by the harbor.
-也许我们应该分开  -这是个坏主意
- Hey, maybe we should split up. - That's a terrible idea.
但是我们要做点什么  对吧
Yeah, but we got to do something, right?
别担心  我在军队受训了四年
Don't worry, I have four years' training in the military.
即使这样  从什么时候起现场调查员配枪了
Uh, even still, since when does a CSI carry a gun?
从怪物出现在我们城市里时起
Since there were monsters in our city.
好吧  朱...
All right, Jul--
感谢
Cheers.
你要走了吗
You're leaving us?
是的
Yeah.
我妈妈和我之间...
Things between my mother and me are...
一言难尽
complicated.
我们可以帮你
We can help you.
科学上面我并不需要帮忙
I don't need your help with the science.
我自己也可以
I can do that on my own.
我来这里想从母亲身上得到的
I came here to get something from my mother
现在我意识到永远也不会得到
that I realize now I'll never get.
你干什么
What are you doing?
对不起  小冰霜
Sorry, Frosty,
你哪儿也不能去
but you're not going anywhere.
让我出去
Let me out of here.
把门打开
Open these doors.
我说了不行
I said no!
我受够了夜以继日的辛苦工作
I am sick of working day after day, night after night,
而我的成果的好处都归给了你母亲
only to have my work benefit your mother.
通过从你那里能得到的信息
With the information I can get from you,
我就总算能离开这里了
I can finally get out of this place,
所以你必须留在这里
so you're gonna stay here
直到我得到我需要的东西
until I get everything that I need.
你不能测试我
You are not going to test me.
我要测试你
Yes, I am.
不  奈杰尔
No, Nigel.
你不能测试我  现在不行  以后也不行
You are not going to test me, now or ever.
等等  放手  快放手
Wait, let go! Let go! Ah!
凯特琳  别这么做
Caitlin! Don't do this!
你不是这样的人
This isn't you!
你对我一无所知  母亲
You don't know anything about me, Mother.
我知道我没有尽到母亲的义务
I-I know I wasn't much of a mother,
我也知道我需要弥补的有很多
and I know I have a lot to make up for,
但是我知道我养大的不是杀手
but I know I didn't raise a killer.
无论有没有意义  我想说我非常抱歉
For whatever it's worth, I am so sorry.
这句话太有意义了
It's worth a lot.
快走吧
Now go.
-那他怎么  -我来处理
- What about-- - I-I'll take care of him.
不会有人发现的  我保证
No one will ever know about this. I promise.
-谢谢你  -快走吧
- Thank you. - Just go.
每次这个怪物一出现
Every time there's been a sighting of the monster,
许多变压器就会爆炸
multiple transformers have blown.
所以它绝对是依靠电力为生的
So it's definitely feeding off electricity.
对  你看我在地图上
Mm-hmm, and see, I mapped out
把它出现过的所有街道标出来了
all the streets that it's been spotted around.
它的活动范围从不会超过十个街区
Never leaves a ten-block radius.
这就是我一直说的
You know, this is exactly what I was talking about.
有些超能力者有幸获得了如此神奇的能力
Some meta's been gifted this incredible power,
结果他们就用来做这种事
and this is the very best thing they can do with it--
恐吓一座城市
terrorize a city.
这  这太可悲了
It's -- It's pathetic.
你究竟是为什么如此憎恨超能力者
Why exactly do you hate metas so much?
如果你觉得我现在会崩溃
If you think I'm gonna break down now
然后告诉你是有一个超能力者杀害了我父母
and tell you that one killed my parents
所以我才会从事这个工作的话
and that's why I have to do this job,
我不会的
I'm not, okay?
艾伦  我憎恨超能力者不需要什么深仇大恨
I don't need a deep, personal reason to hate metas, Allen.
我就看着他们一个接一个的转变
I just need to see person after person transformed,
获得这些神奇的能力
given these extraordinary abilities,
却挥霍这样的能力
and watch them be squandered.
抢劫银行  伤害平民  制造恐惧
Robbing banks, hurting people, spreading fear.
这  这已经不仅仅是犯罪了
It's just-- well, it's not just a crime.
这是一种浪费
It's an absolute waste.
你能想象要是获得了这些超能力
I mean, can you imagine
你会成为什么样子吗
what it would be like to have those powers?
我会用来帮助人们
I mean, I would be helping people.
我会用来改变世界
I would be improving the world.
看来我并不是有幸被选中的少数人  是吧
I guess I wasn't one of the chosen few, was I?
就因为这个
That's it?
你憎恨他们就因为你没有超能力
You're mad at them because you weren't chosen?
抱歉  我只是说说而已
Sorry, I mean, I'm just saying,
成为一个超能力者肯定不容易
it can't be easy being a meta-human,
你的生活  他们的生活会因此发生
having your life--their lives change in ways that,
我们都无法想象的转变
you know, neither one of us could possibly imagine.
肯定需要一些适应时间
It's got to take some adjusting.
好吧  所以现在你还帮他们说话了
Right. So now you're defending them?
不是  我  我只是觉得
Well, no, I mean, I'm-- I don't think that--
我们现在这种实习生什么的  结束了
This internship thing we're doing is completely over.
随便你吧
Whatever.
-变压器是关键  -我同意
- Transformers are the key. - No, I agree--
每次这个怪物一出现
Anytime the monster's shown up,
-周边的变压器全都会爆炸  -它们爆炸
- any nearby have exploded. - They blow up.
车辆警报器也用不了了
Car alarms keep malfunctioning too.
汽车报警器  变压器  究竟有什么联系
Car alarms, transformers. What is the connection?
我们会想出来的  伙计们  会想出来的
Yeah, we'll get there, fellas. We'll get there.
只需要不懈地努力
We just got to keep trying.
也许是有人把变压器的电力输出来
Maybe someone's pulling power out of the transformers
然后以此来为怪物提供能量
and using it to power the monster.
电力  没错  那怪物
Power-- yes, the monster.
你刚好比我抢先一步想出来  三藩西斯科
That's--ah, you just beat me to it, San Francisco.
但这是不可能的  HR
See, that can't be it, H.R.
-不可能  -因为这样我们就会在电网里
- Can't be it-- - 'Cause we would have detected
-检测到电涌  -我们没有检测到
- a surge in the power grid. - We did not.
除非是无线能量传输
Not if it was broadcast power
或是类似于便携式特斯拉塔之类的
or something like a portable Tesla tower.
便携式特斯拉电力
A portable Tesla power.
-是塔  -塔  就是这个
- Tower. - Tower. That's what it is.
棒极了  团队合作  是不是
Nice. Mm, mm. Teamwork, hmm?
再说一句  在我来的那个地球
So PS, where I'm from, on my Earth,
我们把这称为问题解决
we call that a problem solved.
我要去喝杯咖啡
I'm gonna go for coffee.
在我那个地球  咖啡灭绝了
On my Earth, the coffee was wiped out
-因为枯萎病  -枯萎病  对
- by blight.- Blight, yeah.
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
他什么忙都没帮上吧  是不是
He didn't really do anything, did he?
谢谢你了
Thank you.
我反应了好久
Took me a while to realize it,
他只是换个说法
but he's just resaying everything
重述我们说的话而已
that we're saying in a different way.
但绳子的主意确实是他出的
No, he did have the idea for the rope.
反向植入
Reverse inception.
他让你觉得绳子的主意是他出的
He made you think he had the idea for the rope,
但是他都没告诉我们怎么用
but he didn't even tell us how to use it.
这次可不能再被打个措手不及了
Okay, well, we're not gonna be caught off guard again.
对他用震波
We should vibe him.
荣幸之至
It'd be my pleasure.
嘿  宝贝女儿
Hey, baby girl.
你最近经常来这里啊
You've been hanging out here a lot lately.
这个怪物在市里横冲直撞
Yeah, well, there's a lot of scared people
许多市民都被吓坏了
with this monster running around the city.
我们会抓住它的  我们从没失手过
Oh, we'll get him. We always do.
是吗  这句话我能引用进我的文章吗
Oh, yeah? Is that a quote I can use for my article?
不能
No.
好吧  试一试总是值得的
All right. It was worth a try.
爸  你知道沃利和我关系还好  对吧
Dad, you know Wally and I are all right, right?
这是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
我们只是想你不要因为我们而不做某些事
We just don't want you to not do things because of us.
我们只是想你也能  找个伴儿
You know, we just want you to...find someone.
我才不要和你谈这个
I'm not having this conversation with you.
爸  那个地检官绝对是看上你了
Dad, that DA is totally into you.
你应该和她约会
You should go out with her.
爱瑞丝  我不需要你来当丘比特
Iris, I don't need you to be Cupid.
我有我的工作
I got my job.
我还有你  巴里  沃利  我很好
I got you, Barry, Wally. I'm good.
我知道  爸  这很好  我只是
I know, Dad, and that's great. I just--
但我坠入爱河之后
Now that I'm falling in love with someone,
我希望你也能拥有同样的美好
I just want you to have the same thing.
乔  向所有特遣队和狙击队发出警报
Joe? Alert every task force and sniper unit.
让他们装备好
Tell 'em to load up.
我该去尖端科技实验室了
I should get to S.T.A.R. Labs.
-发生什么了  -艾伯特觉得
- What's up? - Albert thinks
他搞清怪物的下一个目标了
he's figured out the creature's next target.
如果有机会
Well, if there's ever an opportunity
让一个40英尺高的怪物搞破坏的话
for a 40-foot monster to wreak havoc,
一定会发生在人们喜欢聚集的地方
it's gonna be where people like to gather.
第二步行街
2nd Street Promenade.
好吧  让我们结束这一切
Well, let's end this.
我正有此意  警探
That's what I intend to do, Detective.
-他去哪儿了  -无所谓
- Where'd he go? - Doesn't matter.
我不需要他
I don't need him.
你这是什么意思  你什么  嘿  哥们
What do you mean? What do you--hey, dude.
你不能随便翻他的东西  这很不
Come on, you can't just go through his stuff; that's not--
我不是在翻他的东西
I'm not going through his stuff.
看  这就是我所担心的
See, this is what I'm talking about.
这到底是什么
What even is this?
现在我似乎赢得了队里大部分人的信任
Now I seem to have won most of the team's trust,
除了三藩西斯科
except Francisco's.
这些是我的东西
Those are my things.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
-什么  -你到底是谁
- What? - Who are you really?
我们知道你在隐瞒什么
We know you're hiding something.
你被骗了  两次
You've been burned, twice...
被一个和我长得一样的男人
by a man with the same face as me.
我猜这种事发生后  你很难信任别人
I imagine it's hard to trust after something like that.
-你也觉得吗  -我真这么觉得
- You think? - I do think.
所以接着播放吧  剩下的部分
So play... the rest of it.
我读过他的日记
I've read his journals.
我找不到任何东西可以告诉我
I found nothing that can tell me
为什么三藩西斯科会有这样的感受
why Francisco feels the way he does,
但我确实希望我能改变
but I do hope I can change
他对哈里森·威尔斯的看法
his opinion of Harrison Wells
然后我们俩也能重建那份友谊
and the two of us can rebuild that friendship.
在这种叙事中可以构造多么棒的故事啊
What a fantastic C-story to weave within the narrative.
什么
What?
什么叙事
What narrative?
叙事手法
Narrative.
我正在写一本小说
I'm writing a novel.
《HR威尔斯的故事》
"The Tales of H.R. Wells."
名字很顺口  对吧
Catchy, I know.
等一下  你是一个科学家兼小说家
Wait, I'm sorry, you're a scientist and a novelist?
-没错  -这真是完美
- Yes. - Wow. That's perfect.
谢谢  确实如此
Thank you. That's exactly right.
我是一名科学家兼小说家
I'm a scientist and a novelist;
我管理着尖端科技实验室
I run S.T.A.R. Labs,
同时也是一名科幻爱情小说作者
and also I'm an author of science-romance.
这是我的定位  写你所熟悉的东西
That's my niche. Write what you know.
所以我就想  "还有什么机会能比
And I thought, "Well, what better opportunity
去另一个地球
than to come to another Earth
写一部关于我的冒险经历的畅销书更好呢"
and pen yet another best seller about my adventures here?"
为什么你不从一开始就告诉我们
Why didn't you just tell us this in the first place?
我觉得那并不重要
I guess it didn't seem relevant,
而且  我以为你们不会
and also, I didn't think you guys
乱翻我的东西
were gonna rifle through my belongings.
就是这样
That's all it is.
我是一名科学家兼小说家
I'm a scientist and a novelist.
你们觉得现在可以信任我了吗
Do you think you can trust me now,
还是说你们地球上
or is that not something
没有信任这种东西
that you have on this Earth, trust?
信任
Trust?
你把我吓了一跳
You scared the dickens out of--
信任谁
Trust who?
软件有反应了
It's the app.
是那个怪物  它回来了
It's the monster. It's back.
-怪物  -是啊 你错过了很多事
- Monster? - Yeah, you've missed a lot.
等我上楼之后再解释
I'll explain upstairs.
好吧  那我就先在这呆着
Well, I'll just stay here, then.
过来吧  我们需要你
Come on. We need you.
好了  我到了
All right, guys. I'm here.
告诉我们你现在看到的一切
Tell us everything that you see right now.
一片狼藉
Mayhem.
还有那个怪物
And the monster.
好了  计划是什么
Okay, so what's the plan?
好问题  韦斯特小姐
Great question, Miss West.
我们制作了一根碳化纤维绳
So we fashioned just a carbon fiber rope,
如果我说错了请纠正我
but correct me if I'm wrong,
我们从来都没讨论过
we never actually discussed
他该怎么用那绳子  对吗
how he was gonna use that rope, did we?
大伙们
Guys.
巴里  我们得上演一出"帝国"了
Barry, we're gonna do "Empire."
"太阳帝国"  巴里
"Empire of the Sun" Barry.
"太阳帝国"  澳洲知名乐队
-什么  是《帝国反击战》  -什么
- What? "Empire Strikes Back." - What?
《星球大战5：帝国反击战》
是《帝国反击战》  巴里
"Empire Strikes Back"" Barry.
像对付帝国步行机一样弄倒它
Just take it down like it was an AT-AT.
就像对付帝国步行机一样
Just like an AT-AT.
"体型越大  摔得越狠"
"Bigger they are, the harder they fall"
连我都看过《帝国反击战》
Even I've seen "Empire."
-我喜欢这样  -我喜欢你
- I like that. - I like you.
好了  开始吧
All right, here we go.
我一直都想做个绝地武士
I always wanted to be a Jedi.
大伙们  绳子直接穿过它了
Guys? Rope went right through it.
它是个全息影像
It's a hologram.
这就解释了一切
That explains everything--
十条街的半径  那些变压器
the ten-block radius, the transformers.
中城电网
稳定运行
它需要那么多的电量才能运行
It takes that much power to render.
等一下  中城警局把狙击队派来了
Wait, CCPD sent snipers there.
如果这不是真的
If it's not real--
那么子弹就会穿过它
Then the bullets will pass right through it.
大伙们  它消失了  它在哪儿
Guys, it's gone. Where is it?
等一下  给我点时间  巴里
Hold on. Give me a sec, Bar.
可我们一秒都等不了了
Okay, we don't have a second!
HR  三角定位怪物的输送信号
H.R., triangulate the signal being sent to the monster.
我们必须中断它  以免它伤害别人
We have to disrupt it before anyone gets hurt.
好的  就那么做  让我们...
Okay, let's do that now. Let's-
让我们三角定位
let's just triangulate.
这电脑无法三角定位
The computer doesn't triangulate...
-什么  -这种信号...
- What? - The signal the way--
不是我习惯的那种...
not the way I'm used to--
这个电脑的规格不能...
this is a different size computer for--
我的天啊  我就知道
Oh, my God. I knew it.
什么
What?
你是冒牌的
You're a fake.
-什么  -什么  -什么
- What? - What? - What?
这么久以来  他一直装作能帮我们
This whole time, he's been acting like he can help us,
但他不能  因为他不知道怎么做  对吧
but he can't because he doesn't now how, does he?
怎么做  三角定位啊
How? Triangulate!
各位  在哪边
Guys, which way?
-走开...  -好的  你来吧
- Get the-- - All right, you take over.
找到了  在第二街和富尔顿街交叉口
Found it. It's at 2nd and Fulton.
第二富尔顿
25楼 强耗电
我已锁定目标
I have a lock on the target.
准备开火
Fire when ready.
停止
Stop!
停止开火  这是全息图
Stop firing! It's a hologram!
停止射击  停止射击
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
是全息图  它哪去了
A hologram? Where'd it go?
韦斯特警探  朱利安呢
Detective West, where's Julian?
他刚还在呢
He was here!
西斯科  把地址告诉我
Cisco, I need that location.
汉米尔顿大楼
25楼 强耗电
汉米尔顿大楼  25楼
Hamilton building, 25th floor.
那里的耗电量
There's more power going there
比大楼其他地方加起来都多
than anywhere else in the building combined.
视线覆盖全部袭击
Line of sight to all the attacks.
他就在那里
That's where he is.
我让你举起手来
I said put your hands up!
中城警局  不许动
This is CCPD! Freeze!
停止你手头的行为
Stop what you're doing!
我说了让你举起手来
I said put your hands up!
你还是个孩子
You're just a kid.
没错  你差点杀死的孩子
Yeah, a kid you almost killed!
你为此会付出代价的  伙计  你会...
You're gonna pay for that one, buddy. You're gonna--
我不这样认为  伙计  我认为是你
Yeah, I don't think so, man; I think you're the one
要为你对这座城的破坏付出代价
that's gonna be paying for all the damage you did to this city
很长久的代价
for a very long time.
闪电侠
Hey, Flash.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
你意识到多少无辜的人
Do you realize how many innocent people
可能因此受伤  甚至丧命
could have been hurt, or worse?
是什么驱使你做出这种事
What made you do something like this?
我只想尝一次强势的滋味
I just wanted to feel powerful for a change.
就因为这个  恐吓他人
And that did it? Scaring people?
对  对  就为这个
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, it did.
学校的那些孩子  他们每天都捉弄我
You know, the kids at my school, they tease me every day.
我就是那里的怪胎
I'm a weirdo there.
我受够了一直担惊受怕的感觉
And I'm just sick of feeling scared all the time.
我只想让别人尝一次这种滋味
I just wanted someone else to feel that way for a change.
是这样  我知道...
Look, I know
你这个年龄  有时会很辛苦
sometimes things are hard at your age.
但相信我  情况会好转的
But trust me, it does get better.
所以现在怎么办
So what happens now?
你要为你的行为要承担一些后果
Well, there are severe consequences for what you did,
而且你只能接受这一点
and you're just gonna have to accept that,
但听着  你还年轻
but listen, you're young.
你还可以改过自新
You can turn all of this around.
好了  走吧
All right. Come on.
你被《科技杂志》授予过
You were named Entrepreneur of the Decade
"十年企业家"称号
by "Tech Magazine"?
-没错  -这里面哪些是真的
- That's right. - Is any of what's on here true?
-全是真的  -怎么会
- All of it. - How?
你连电脑都不会开
You can barely turn on a computer.
每个创意都有两个部分
There are two parts to every idea.
包括建立和执行
There is the inception and the execution.
我负责前者
I provide the former.
所以你负责想出创意
So you come up with the ideas?
对  我不知道如何实施
Yeah, I don't know how to implement them.
我是创意者
I'm the idea man.
所以实际上不是你破解了我们发的密码
So you didn't actually solve the cryptogram that we sent you?
对  是我那里尖端科研实验室的搭档
No, that was my partner at S.T.A.R. Labs on my Earth.
我是公司的脸面
I'm the face of the company.
我其实是公司幕后的灵感来源
I'm more of the inspiration behind the company.
然后我暴露了
Then I was exposed.
人们认为我有某种成就
people thought that I was something
实际上没有
that I-I guess I wasn't.
总之  对我来说难以承受
Anyway, it kind of all fell apart for me.
然后我收到了你们的消息
But then I got your message.
我的搭档给我看了你们的消息
My partner brought me your message.
我意识到  他给了我一次机会
I realized he's bringing me an opportunity
来这个地球写这本书的机会
to come to this Earth to write this book.
多元宇宙中有这么多星球
So many planets in the multiverse,
我们偏偏选中了那个
and we happen to pick the one Wells
不是科学家的威尔斯
who's not a scientist.
没错
You're right.
我之对你没完全坦白
I wasn't completely honest with you--
对你们大家
with all of you.
我感到很抱歉  很后悔
I feel badly about that. I regret that.
但我来问你个问题
But let me ask you a question.
你们当中就没人为了顾全大局
Has there been none amongst you that has ever shaded the truth
而隐瞒过真相吗
for what you believe to be the greater good?
依我看你像个骗子
It sounds to me like you're a con man.
对
Yeah.
如果我是骗子
Was I a con man
我会告诉三藩西斯科
when I showed San Francisco here
如何用汽车警报追踪怪兽吗
how to track the beast using car alarms?
如果我是骗子  我会告诉他
Was I a con man when I showed him
如何用碳素纤维拧成绳子吗
how to fashion a rope using carbon fiber?
这些都是我想出的点子
I came up with those ideas!
你是受我的建议启发的
You were prompted by my suggestions.
创意就是这么起作用的
That is how ideas work!
伙计们  你们需要一位缪斯
People, you need a Muse!
我可以成为你们的缪斯
I can be your Muse.
阻止你所在地球上所有超能力者怎么样
What about stopping all the metas on your Earth?
对我来说就不止是一个顾问角色了
More of an advisory role for me,
但我当时在那里
but I was there.
我记得我们如何...
I remembered how we--
你们不认为那说明了什么吗
you don't think that's something?
我来给你们情景还原
Let me present you with a scenario.
你们在和一个东西对峙
You're confronted with something,
那是你们从未遇到过的威胁
a threat that you've never seen before.
你们不知道如何阻止它  谁知道呢
You don't know how to stop it. Who does?
这对你们而言就是价值
That's value to you.
让我向你们证明自己的价值
Let me prove my worth to you.
如果失败了  我就灰溜溜地回去自己的地球
If I fail, I will "Pfft" right back to my Earth,
但如果成功了  我肯定会成功
but if I succeed, I will have succeeded
不仅能恢复自己的名誉  而且...
not just in redeeming myself but also...
还在自己的生命中做了善举
will have done some good with my life.
你很幸运  我们在这里
You know, you're lucky we're pretty big
很擅长做补救和善举
on redemption and doing good here,
所以我觉得你可以...  我不知道...
so I think you can-- I don't know--
待上几周  尝试证明自己
stay for a few weeks, try to prove yourself,
但如果行不通  你就灰溜溜地回你的地球吧
but if not, "Fyoo," back to your Earth.
谢谢你
Thank you.
别再重新包装了
No more repackaging.
一言为定
Word is bond.
别再那样就好
That-- just no more that.
-好了  HR  -好的
- All right, H.R. - Okay.
你去哪儿了
Where you been?
其实我去拜访我妈了
I actually went to visit my mother.
你妈妈
Your mother?
天呐  怎么了
Oh, boy. Why?
看看我们是否能一起解决一个问题
To see if we could work through some of our issues.
我觉得我们的关系可能正在慢慢修复中
And I think we might actually be on the road to recovery.
涉及到家事时  你得竭尽一切努力
When it comes to family, you got to do whatever it takes,
因为有一天  你可能再也没机会那么做了
'cause one day, you might not be able to do that anymore.
很高兴你回来了
Glad you're back.
这里就是家
This is home.
我今晚差点杀了一个孩子
I nearly killed a kid tonight.
我们追踪的怪物
The monster we were chasing,
原来只是一个全息图
it turns out it was just a hologram,
而操作者是个15岁的男孩
operated by a 15-year-old boy.
闪电侠赶来拯救了一切
Flash came to save the day.
他拯救了我  阻止我去...
And he saved me from doing something--
我听说了
I heard.
你知道悲伤的部分是什么吗
You know what's sad?
那个孩子  他那样做只是因为他很害怕
That kid, he's just acting 'cause he's scared, you know?
他想让大家都害怕
He wants everyone to be terrified
让大家见到怪物就跑
and to run away from the monster
这样他就感觉自己很强大
so he can feel powerful.
我知道那个感觉
I know what that's like.
什么意思
How do you mean?
我来自一个很富裕的家庭
I come from a pretty wealthy family...
在英格兰
back in England.
我们家族是传统的贵族
It's a long line of generations of old money,
有悠久的传统  其实都没什么意义
tradition-- nonsense, really.
而我当时是继承人  我是长子
And I was the heir. I was their firstborn son.
我本该继承很多家产
I was supposed to inherit the lot.
但我是个怪人
But I was the odd duck...
宁愿去花园里
who would rather go in the garden
收集各种昆虫标本
and collect samples of insects....
而不是去学习如何
rather than learn how to tie
打好一个温莎结
a Windsor knot
或者晚宴时该先用哪一把叉子
or which fork to use first at dinner.
对  我想要更多
Yeah. No, I wanted more.
你明白吗
You know?
我来这里做的事
I came here to do the one thing
是他们无法阻止我的
that they couldn't stop me from doing:
成为一个科学家  一个伟大的科学家
becoming a scientist-- becoming a great scientist.
而就在我到达这个领域的顶端时
And then just as I got to the top of my field,
世界在一夜之间改变了
the world changes overnight.
超能力者
Meta-humans.
我对超能力者一无所知
I don't know a single thing about meta-humans.
我不知道他们说话与走路的方式
I don't know how they talk. I don't know how they walk.
我当然不知道阻止他们该
I certainly don't know the first thing
先做什么  所以我毫无用处
about stopping them, so... rendered useless.
我猜那就是现在我所逃避的怪物
I suppose that's the monster that I'm running from now:
就是无力感
just feeling powerless.
有些时候我也有这个感觉  朱利安
Yeah, I feel the same way some days, Julian.
我幼时丧母
I lost my mom when I was a kid.
最近父亲也过世了
Lost my dad recently.
这是个可怕的世界  身边的人在死去
It's a scary world. People die.
信任被背叛  一切都在改变
Trusts are betrayed. Things change.
但改变也可能是件好事  你知道吗
But change can be a good thing, you know?
它可以带来新的体验与机会  让你结识新人
It can bring new experiences, new opportunities, people.
你可以把他们当作潜在的敌人
You can treat 'em like a potential enemy
或者新朋友
or like a new friend.
让自己相信一切都会好起来吧
Just trust that everything's gonna be okay.
也许你是对的
Yeah, maybe you're right.
别收拾了
You can stop.
你可以留下
You can stay.
关于闪电侠我真的错了
I was really wrong about The Flash,
所以对你的成见可能也是错的
so I could be wrong about you too.
晚安  同事
Good night, mate.
朱利安
Julian?
要不要一起喝一杯
You want to get a drink?
好啊  很乐意
Yeah. Yeah, I'd like that.
好  我们走
All right. Let's do it.
凯特琳  我在过我们采集到的数据中
Caitlin, I've been going over the data we collected,
发现了一些让人疑惑的结果
and I found some disconcerting results.
你体内化学成分所发生的变化
Your body's chemistry is changing in ways
我无法完全理解  但有一件事很明确
that I don't fully understand, but one thing is clear.
你所拥有的的能力  你使用的越频繁
These powers you have, the more you use them,
就越难逆转到之前的状态
the more difficult they're going to be to reverse.
我很遗憾  宝贝  但听我说
I'm sorry, honey, but listen to me.
任何情况下都不要再使用你的超能力了
You must not use these powers under any circumstances.